hello YouTube alright hello youtube
welcome to fix our world Friday where
the three of us are gonna fix our world
in the next hour that's our that's our
agenda
let's just be on the agenda every every
week fix the world fix the world check
um yeah
Jonas is joining us again today he has a
very similar project that we are doing
our project raising evil his prep whose
project raising the project raising on
his project kinda kind act and although
you pronounce it differently right when
I was reading their like it can't
pronounce in different ways but tomorrow
I was saying before we went live that
like last week was a good learning
experience like Jasper brought a lot of
insight he's a very intelligent person
but it wasn't our board meeting right
like it wasn't moving our project
forward because we didn't have an agenda
lined out for a guest to come be part of
and yeah just I have it on her agenda
for this week to discuss like if we have
future guests what does that look like
to empower both them and us to move
forward or maybe I'm wrong and yesterday
was last week was perfect it was moving
us forward I don't know how did you feel
about it I am struggling to remember
last week actually I think you're right
that we didn't we didn't really move
forward so but I'm trying to remember
why that was so because we're discussing
his ideas mostly or I think I kind of
got in a bit debate about how to move
forward in a certain way sort of right
we were instructed not talking about
Microsoft garetty's I think what we were
looking to talk about and then instead
it was more explaining together tech and
in his opinion our lack of direction
which is our direction it's like we're
exploring new ways to every time to move
forward in like what is working and
what's not working and so I think you
wanted to talk about micro solidarity
and I wanted to talk about solutions
cooperative and how we turn this time
spot this hour we
together into how do we create solutions
whether that's for together tech itself
or for the worlds called fix our world
Friday's like how does this hour
actually move together tech forward and
create solutions using us and I go my
crystal linearity is a great way like
that is kind of they were very
intertwined so thinking that through I
think one of the challenges was that his
a guest had more questions that he
didn't already have answered before so
if the board meeting is a constructive
meeting then we do need to make sure
that everyone has had an opportunity to
get those out so maybe having you know
it wouldn't be like a perspective board
meeting or someone would be more like it
let's give them a time to come in and
talk and answer ask and ask questions
maybe outside the board meeting make
sure that we're all kind of aligned
before we kind of move forward in the
board meeting yeah but that's just a but
I'm just throwing that out there I don't
know if that work yeah no I think that
was part is like our agendas with the
two of us is fine like we're like well
throw it together five minutes
beforehand what we want to talk about I
think it works for the two of us when a
third person comes in to that they don't
and that's part of figuring it so right
is as more people we have to home as
where people are added permanently and
just on a in a no basis to figure out
that piece of it as different
personality these people don't have we
don't have the blurb of like here's what
we're doing looks like it's ever
evolving and that is is in my opinion
kind of the project is that when things
don't work we fix them and figure them
out and try new things and most of what
we're creating is chicken and egg like
if what we were creating existed we
wouldn't need to create it we could use
it to create everything else but which
piece do we play first and how do we do
that within our capacity our time our
money the people involved you know about
that piece of it and working through
that every week but I don't like I
there's something we can do during this
hour that is kind of putting it on the
back burner well still moving it forward
kind of like with project raising we are
finding the
in pain right like project raising is
moving our project forward just in a
different way we're focusing on someone
else's project and finding that common
pain and there's something that for that
here in the other tag like having people
come on board and help us move it
forward but dealing with like actual
solutions that aren't necessarily
together tech like there and I put out
on game be an alpha point and my own
personal page and I tweeted something
about creating a conference for a food
conference on zero slaves and three tons
of carbon and I basically thought that
crickets hey there was no and I don't
quite I mean I got some people respond
to you know I got just frustrated
yesterday cuz I was like I'm not
explaining this Velux like oh yeah we're
doing that we sold food like no because
it isn't about the solving food it's
about coming together and creating a
solution having everyday people not
experts right not current permaculture
people and people who like know they
know food it's like everyone eats so
what are you currently doing and how do
we co-create something that is Omni wind
that is both bringing down our
footprints of slavery and carbon but
also bringing up our nutrition right no
you don't I mean like not because all of
the solutions to carbon and slavery's
like you pay more money you know just
grow your own food
buy from farmers market and those aren't
accessible whereas no matter what your
diet is if we were able to have a
discussion and not be shamed for it and
figure out ways to move forward that's
why I outlines on there what how I
thought a conference would go and I'm
still gonna hold the same call on Monday
we'll see if anyone shows up but um like
something like that here but it still is
I don't know like I don't know how to
make this time be how do we focus on a
solution and showcase that anyone can
have an opinion and that's the power is
that isn't that my opinion Trump's your
opinion it's that I get to you know like
I get to be empowered in my diet you got
to be empowered in your diet and we get
to own that our diets cost the world
carbon enslaves you know like how can we
reduce that while still making choices
in our own lives
so our Jonas go ahead if you ever am I
haven't yet thought directly on that one
but more on a such generally for me I
always like to do something practical
along with the theoretical thinking to
you know kind of prove with a terror
theory is actually working out or not
and so I really like that idea and I was
even thinking of having this as part of
this meeting here to think about one
example how we would deal with bringing
one or let's say we have three projects
or so how we would deal with those three
projects how we would move something for
what and then you know going along with
this kind of example to figure out where
our processes of finding solutions
finding out what take we want to create
together whether that works and yeah I
think it's really it would be really
good if we have this kind of conferences
and yeah project raising I guess as well
as part of it to go along with this
fixing the world Friday what making what
meeting um yeah maybe all that in a
little bit more structure or more
obvious way so that people know how good
this is all going along I mean of course
this is only evolving as we speak um so
I guess it wasn't super consciously
going along together but maybe from now
on that could be so that's I guess
brainstorming what this space could look
like that is solutions focused but also
fun
engaging to be part of both hopefully to
watch but that's never the priority and
that's where like I had this idea in my
head when I put out the conference that
like tons of people want to join it but
they'll be a handful of people who want
to actually create the conference and I
need the people to help create the
conference don't referred to actually be
hosted and there wasn't interest in
either I was like is this not and that's
the same with like the it's the
scheduling tool I'm like I know that
people need this the world needs it to
have a social media thing that actually
connects people so people can talk to
each other it's just about the
underlining infrastructure but there's
also like are we wrong am I wrong like
do people not want that and we just
created it for like the two of us and I
I don't see that because everyone who
experiences the idea cafe everyone who
has a conference of starting a
conversation and game being that is game
be like that is where the magic happens
is in the conversations is in the not
watching other people having
conversations but actually having them
and getting to bring your ideas to it to
a group and to able to harness that and
be able to generate ideas and a group of
100 but the point of the conference
wasn't to figure out the food system it
was to showcase that together we can
brainstorm and some ideas can come out
of it and we can also do microsoft
linearity like form groups in between
these conferences that might happen
every two months and figure out like
what's something that sparked you that
you wanted to move forward with whether
that's creating a garden with ten people
or creating a technology system with
10,000 people like what comes out of it
and that's from the theoretical to the
real like unless people unless we're
able to get people to the conference
we can't play there right like we can't
have that and figure out how does that
move forward and stream yard has both
personal boundary of like people don't
necessarily want to do it live right
they don't necessarily want to be live
on YouTube but also there can only be up
to six of us having a conversation
whereas Zune can have a hundred people
we can go into breakout rooms we can
actually play with it and try but like
everything we don't have the tool to
easily connect people to those groups
and get people there and it's
just about like trying and failing in
the right direction continually yeah it
also kind of reminds me about every
other idea I've ever had where the first
couple times I reach out and show it to
people I do don't usually get crickets
so I don't know if this is just part of
the maturity model of ideas where you
find how to phrase it in a way that
people understand it with very little
energy on their part in a way that they
feel empowered or challenged or however
I want to say it so it's just a thought
I had I was looking at your post to see
if I could see anything obvious because
it is surprising how often you'll write
something and people just read it wrong
like everyone reads it wrong it's like
that's not what this because I think
even when I first read this I think I
was skimming so I thought this was a
conference when really you're just
talking about creating a conference yeah
yes and that's fairly obvious with the
way you wrote it whoever I switched it
like because Colleen and someone else
had been auditioning single names but
like two people had comments on and put
the stuff I was like clearly I'm not
being clear so I swapped it and I put
the new Facebook group in the comments
and the document what I've written in
the document in the in the post of like
hey this is a conference right I'd like
to have these five questions and work
through this process then go out into
you know form groups I want to get
together and discuss that is that right
and then like how would we get people
into groups how do we get a hundred
people or even twelve people to a
conference what does the conference look
like right are these good questions to
start with and work through that process
together and there's something broken
there like there's something that's like
the non hierarchical decision-making or
I don't want someone to come in and say
this is how we fix the food system
I want everyone who eats at the table
saying here's what I'm currently doing
in and then together figuring out what
isn't next step we could do right what
could we do with 10 people it's like a
thought experiment that hopefully enacts
enough actual interest to create
something but that's not the point right
the point isn't to create the app that
fixes our food system it's to see how
that conversation generates an idea and
I thought I was putting that out there
but not clearly and honest I see your
comments there I'm just I think it is
what I'm talking about when just like
it's like how to actually fix the food
system as opposed to how to like create
this space into a solution generating
our and/or how to do that off of this
and use this to get people there like I
really like our project raisi I think
that's awesome and I'm enjoying having
these conversations but there's
something about it switching to a
solutions cooperative that we can do in
this space of like everyone's invited
how do we use this hour to create a
solution together and specifically this
hour where this meaning we're having
right now or or the Saturday project
raising or a separate hour or I guess
you're talking about that to fix our
world Friday out like what does that
look like where we were designing it
kind of around a board meeting with an
agenda which might be what we keep right
that might be the most powerful
iteration but to be able to say how
could we play with this our
how can it be fun to come and create a
solution together that is solution
generating the issue is if there's only
three or four of us or two of us that
it's not an idea cafe right even idea
cafe isn't an idea the point of it was
to be like this is one table of a
conversation there's supposed to be
three four or five other tables at least
having the same conversation and then
switching and having this you know same
conversation again and building don't
lean on that till we get to a point
creating actual solutions and then out
of that like let's say there's 100
people participate in the conference not
all hundred in one meeting
smaller group so no hundred are gonna
want to work on any project live alone
whichever one is the most powerful I
just want to play in that space like I
want to have a hundred people come and
be part of a conversation and then
explain how that was for them so that we
can make that process better and create
the technology so that it can be a
million people having a conversation how
they create their food system because
right now it is very top-down it's like
I have an idea and how do I get it out
into the world as opposed to how can we
create an idea together so that we
already have the marketing we already
have the funding because we have the
people generating it who are that's
right they're both the people using it
at the market like they're all of it in
one but you first need a group of people
and the process has to be fun enough
that it's a natural attractor and I
think the conference if there were
people there would be that because we
can also it's a seed and then it can
improve but I don't know how to
communicate it to get the people there
and I jumped I said how do you get the
people there or the people here and do
we need the people here what does this
look like yeah I'm wondering actually
with a um so your initial call about
those projects for a project raising it
did get like I don't know 20 30 projects
so I'm proposed and so people they I
think people have their own projects
that I really like to work on and it's
much easier to get them involved on
their own projects as opposed to okay
here's one project I want you all to
join and let's fix this one together
because that one is not theirs
yeah and so so I'm I'm wondering how can
we create basically your post of hey
what's your project what do you want to
work on into this
um life online sphere here and then
split out from there yeah yeah and that
is like that is in what is like sitting
inside is like that people love their
own project and that's where like the
food idea was people love food that is
you right like that isn't your project
but it's something that it's intertwined
in every area of your life and so but I
don't it's not their project it's not
them it's not their lives and so to be
able to bring maybe that is it maybe
it's a conference on projects maybe it's
a conference on not not find people with
you for your project but like come and
tell us what makes projects hard for you
right like maybe creating a conference
like that around projects that isn't
focusing on one project and how do we
raise it but is focusing on does that
make like maybe that is the piece yeah I
like that idea that the meta one metal
level above our project raising is then
how do we create that which is what
we've been talking about really I'm
think of it how do we create
infrastructures that will make these
projects easier and maybe not
infrastructure so it could just be
lessons it could just be documentation
it could you know what what can we go
create to make these projects yes
partly because I was like and then we
cuz maybe if we have what I was
envisioning for the food one was every
other week or sorry every other month
having like a conference on a Saturday
for however many hours to go through
these questions and rotate tables and
then forming smaller groups that you
meet weekly with if you want to to be
able to either move an idea forward or
whatever that looks like and I don't
know if this was during our project
raising our brainstorming one or whether
who I had this conversation with but the
idea of bringing like there's so many
good like reasons score and we
collection and there's things that are
very tied together their food ones
they're like actually having those
people coordinator and stay together to
say just like kind of like what we were
doing before project raising with me my
brother of like goal setting like the
group can decide right with micro
solidarity they can say how do we
support each other in these smaller
groups what are our call
maybe they'd find a way to create 19
reasons for meets wiki election needs
and creating together tech like the
infrastructure underneath that is the
marketing and funding and all of these
all of these things together and it's so
funny to think we have more people in
game B with their own project who are
willing to come and be part of a
conference on that then there are people
who eat but there was also you can't
spin it in it like I'm like zero slaves
and three tons of carbon is how do we
get rid of the negative instead of how
do we draw in the positive right like I
don't know the positive span of like how
do we create abundance without stepping
on people the environment it's still the
negatives still in that spin and I think
creating your project it's gonna bring
up all the emotion it's still gonna
bring up ideas and but it's not we can
it's an easier thing to state positively
and drawing people I think so one
thought I'm having but I it may be
because I'm misunderstanding I I would
think that a good place to start for
this for the food idea is to have it do
a project raising so do it on a Saturday
and then we figure out in that meeting
how to continue that part which doesn't
inch a question on what this meetings
supposed to be but but how does it what
does that resonate with you at all yeah
my only worry was like our next Saturday
that's free is like four five Saturdays
from now I theoretically cuz like
tomorrow well you could always become a
dictator and just say three weeks is
Jasper Skye and then we're doing the
podcast of Daniels head is named for
ones from then but I don't want to be a
dictator but maybe we can make this into
our project crazy for that next week
maybe we can put a call out for this is
a project raising for that and invite
people does that resonate with people
like that seems it's more focus like
we're talking about with the agenda yeah
fine with that and then but to answer
your question about about what fix our
word Friday's would be I guess I have
two thoughts on that one is it's that
meta time where we talk about how what
can we do and maybe get more you know
the may this is something that everyone
in a project should be participating in
saying what can we do to make to move
all of our projects forward with I hate
to say faster because everything's
getting faster I really wanted maybe
more efficiently we want to kind of
grease the wheels a bit it doesn't have
to be higher speed just you know being
able to make more movement with less
people pushing or get more people
involved more resources just working
yeah I think this would be good which
although I guess maybe we should change
the name to fix our world Friday to the
other one but because that that Nate I
don't know that that name fits if it's
really the meta project project yeah
that was always a placeholder anyway
yeah I still like I do like having the
idea of having a meta project project
meeting and then having a a single
project raising or people bring up a new
idea and then I think there's a time for
I don't know if this is part of the meta
project project or not but at a time
where everybody who's running a project
can come in and say you know do a
regular mastermind you know where
everyone does a five-minute update on
where their project is and what's going
on and then you usually depend on the
side of the group have one person in the
hot seat and they get like 20 minutes
two or 30 minutes and they can bring up
a specific issue that they're having in
their project and everyone brainstorms
the solution so I think those three
meetings would is an idea that that
sounds good to me right now is the idea
all three of them would be weekly or one
of them is like monthly and one of those
times was are they all an hour weekly
for three meeting sounds like quite a
bit I would think the project were
raising we have enough projects that we
really need to keep that Weekly
I do know that a lot of people have
masterminds every other week so I'm have
every week the Mehta project
I mean maybe it'd be good to do
alternating I don't know if this confuse
people
but alternating wear and maybe that
would work out really good so one week
it's like this is our mastermind we talk
about what's happening in our projects
we we can mention a small issue in case
someone has a quick solution and then
someone gets a hot seat before there's
actually quite a few mastermind formats
we could try them and then I have that
alternating with the weeks where we just
have an open discussion of what's what
some central tech or resources or ideas
that we can that we would all of our
projects would benefit from so maybe
that way it wouldn't be three meetings
every week for three hours already have
a whole job just know I'd like that idea
also there was something about like what
the conference for food again I'm not
tied to a food conference I'm more tied
to a conference that like there's a way
to bring us together and break us into
groups to have the idea cafe or
iterations on that of like you get to
meet with other people there's a power
to meeting with new people there's a
power to having the same group right I
think a mastermind group is the same
group nante who was big conference with
like the congregation in micro
solidarity and then you you form your
smaller groups and there's something
there where like the smaller groups are
the mastermind group and then maybe this
is our mastermind group that we have
every other week with whoever our little
group is and then we maybe have a
conference every two months
for like a Saturday morning right that'd
be inside of a Saturday morning you
don't have a project raising that week
but but Pete everyone with this is a
meta right some people with projects are
coming to that and forming that and
we're figuring out right I don't know
how many of us there are hopefully
there's at least 12 of us but how do we
move our projects forward and then also
for mastermind groups and as we grow
like I don't even think it seems to be
game B I have people in my life with
projects who are game B projects like my
brother owns a baby but like you know
what I mean like initially it was but
love of like bring a friend who has who
has a project right so that we can grow
that conference and those people can
form groups and support each other and
keep our Saturday project raising I mean
I'm loving all of this
like it's it's a good trial something to
try out I don't know how to communicate
today because it's really not my forte
good but I feel like this also doesn't
get what the food one did which was even
when Ernesto was doing is like here are
solutions to food which is not I can
think up solutions to food we can all
think up solutions to food but then
they're hierarch to call it's like you
need to go vegan or uni insist we need
to stop transporting food everywhere as
opposed to like what are we doing and
how do we actually improve it and I
think that does naturally drawing people
if it's your project you're gonna own it
it's gonna be your baby you're gonna
want to not necessarily change it at the
same time see the meta part piece of it
like right but if we fix marketing well
what's interesting about your your
project the the food project
I shouldn't say you're I guess since
you're trying to co-create it is that
manure goal of not being kind of hard
hierarchically driven I guess really
what I could think about it is this is
place for brain people brainstorm ideas
that other people could choose
individually on the individual ideas to
implement or not implement right so it's
really kind of like co-creating a
resource of tools of the wrong word
options you know for you to get closer
to East so that each individual can
exercise their sovereignty and get into
in you know how and move more towards
fewer slaves and fewer carbons yeah and
there's probably a whole ton of topics
that could use that format right so it
that wouldn't work so much for our tech
cooperative because we actually want to
build something physical it's you do
need to the things people build have to
fit together but for your thing towards
just like here's just a list of things
that individuals can each do and we'd
all be moving the collective forward
that's as I just never really thought of
that as a
that's interesting it's more like this
space in between I have to fix my own
problem right like I have to figure out
how to get to zero slaves it's not
possible I can't do that like food
system you might be able to if you live
off the land
but if you're having this conversation
on a computer you're using slaves like
our whole computer system is based on
and so to be able to Disney can make
concrete decisions in and it's much
easier to tackle our food choices than
our energy choices right like I'm not
gonna rebound my entire house I'm a
renter so it's like we're both have more
access to those choices like I know
where I shop I know what I'm doing for
food I know the impact that's having on
my body and and more easily than I do
with my clothing or you know I mean is
just an easier spot to start with um but
it is this space between I have to solve
my own problems and the government or
the big other has to solve them or I
have to figure out how to get the big
other to solve them right like we have
to come together and demand they change
laws which people are working on that
area I'm not saying not to but there's
this huge space in-between of like how
what could ten of us do together it may
be start a community garden
what could a hundred of us do together
we could start a cohousing dinner right
like or find a community kitchen and
have collective dinners where we're
sharing in our food and resources and
bringing that number down
what can 10,000 of us do together within
one city and not necessarily creating
those things but just brainstorming and
just seeing like what is possible with
that and then it naturally to me leads
to tech like oh wait but how would you
coordinate with ten thousand people ten
people you can coordinate with but ten
thousand you need the tech and then the
men it comes in right of like well
that's create the scheduler let's create
the way to have these conversations to
find the people and yeah so it wasn't so
tied to the food it was tied to the
bringing that space between I need to
solve it and they need to solve it like
what can we actually do that is powerful
and so part of that was what are you
doing like I'm I have things that both
don't work my food system like I used to
eat a lot of processed food because it's
what's easy and convenient cheap and
then I also have things that really work
like oh housing and just creating even a
list of like well not everyone can have
Co housing but it's a thing that exists
quest exists which is a non-profit
grocery store in Vancouver if you know
Vancouver you can't use it you have to
have a you have to be poor to use it
basically but that's a thing that could
be started in any city right if people
got together and said oh this is you
know like a tool library there are ways
to coordinate between the US and them
and I think coming together and having
those conversations naturally draws in
the energy someone who knows how to
create a database to be like oh yeah
let's create that right like the
conversation anyone can be part of or
it's like here's what I'm doing
here's what works for me and here's what
would need to be in place for other
people to do that not anyone can come
and eat at our dinner at cohousing but
anyone could start a community dinner
why you coordinate with your neighbors
you could find what does that look like
and I just want to be able to have the
conversation and food was just the thing
that I thought would draw in everybody
because it's food and instead it drew in
nobody yeah and I was I was thinking and
just feel free to interrupt if I'm
hugging the replies that there I think
there are some wording that might bring
people a little bit more I think maybe I
don't see it here anymore initially like
when we're using the word solution it
sounds like we need to find a better
word than that which I think you
mentioned earlier because it's Royd more
like brainstorming or something but
that's not even processed like a process
cooperative solutions yeah I like the
idea of like iterative or or
experimental or there's got to be some
sort of word for that I'm just gonna
read what you wrote for his and change
the wording and evolve my professed to
collaborate and discuss sustainable omni
wind solutions for our most for food and
promote and manage our implementation
the closest thing to an elevator pitch
for anything yeah but yeah yeah so yeah
and then there was one other little
tweak to it if I think if it's in
brainstorm ideas that we can because
still does sound like you're talking
about you know collectively to get to
zero slaves kind of like making society
to it which your focus is more
empowering individuals to do it and then
society hopefully I'll show you follow
that methods optimization yeah I don't
like it so there's all like close to and
not quite the right because all of them
like every word has been co-opted so
like yeah but like I must invent a new
one and then explain it to everyone
constant yeah and then yeah and then we
have a lot of problems like I don't like
I know like I think I'll me wins great
but if I say that to a lot of people I
really have to explain it even though
it's in the word depends on their their
vocabulary a lot of people don't
understand prefixes and stuff for me is
great but this is maybe an iteration of
like how can we responsible in the City
instead of off-grid advocate for modular
possibility in apartments etc like what
what can we actually do ourselves to
sorry did I take that off before you're
taking it I mean that's good um yeah
like to draw in people secure I'm also
not the best at asking questions like I
kind of asked him to answer it in the
same thing instead of like listening and
that's what I'm trying to do is like
we're asking the question like what are
you doing for food and how can you
improve it without hierarchically
imposing that on anyone without saying
like although we need a mcdonalds
solution solved everyone goes vegan like
we can't solve it for other people which
is why this process of us meeting to fix
the world doesn't work like work is what
we're discussing is how to create a
process that brings in people so they
can fix it for themselves right so they
can fix their own piece of it without
requiring anyone else like it's an
invitation it's an invitation to help
problem solve and word keeps coming up
an invitation like a solutions
invitation cooperative but like if
that's not doesn't work
yeah I don't know if I have much more to
add on that I also I thought I guess I
don't really have anything to add to
that specifically um a few things that I
could say about your food things
specifically why for example I didn't
join was I just realized that I was
mainly thinking food I have food I don't
need to solve food what what's that you
know I eat I I don't see that as a
pressing problem even though of course
framed in your way of you know carbon
and slices of course it's still a
problem but yeah I mean at the same time
then yeah for me of course I have my own
other project so I'm not yeah I want to
spend my time rather on my project and
on on your project but having said that
I
I would probably really appreciate
having some some really good overview if
we create a spreadsheet of all the
projects all the problems that we
identified and so and then people could
associate themselves with the problems
that they want to think about so we have
a few problems and then you see problem
a two people are interested problem B 10
people are interested problem C nobody's
really interested but then from there on
you can organize a little bit better
those projects that many people are
interested and potentially reframe those
projects that people are not that
interested in and then from there on you
can have those breakout sessions and
things like that
sorry I'm always quiet I'm thinking in
concrete terms no I think that would be
awesome but the issue is like I came
like a spreadsheet and everyone adds
their name and checks off what their
problems are they care about which one
has the most checks but even getting
people to fill that out isn't it's
crickets like you know what I mean like
it's like people how do we get them to
that spreadsheet to fill that out to see
what's the what's the most pressing
problem and then some of them can't be
solved with this method and some of them
can be like everyone wants to give their
solution for the world like well
everyone just needs to and I do too
everyone needs to follow my lead right
like everyone needs to go begin everyone
needs to ride a bike I can do it why
can't everyone else instead of here's
what I'm doing and if I'm so up on my
high horse that I'm doing good and no
like it's not actually a solution like
buying carbon offsets isn't a solution
because people can't afford it and the
very people who are creating the most
carbon can't afford it not the rich
people like but you know people who are
mining because they don't have food to
eat like though that like how people who
like you didn't know you had a food
problem right you kind of maybe knew you
and that's why I kind of said it like
slaves and carbon like I want people who
care about that as a problem without
concentrating on that as a problem then
we were spending too much of this our
concentrated on the food conference but
it's part of it it's like how to get
people on board and I do almost with the
spreadsheet for um projects right I
don't I don't know if there's one in
game B of like everyone's project and
what it is and other people's projects
they're pretty game B we kind of we're
thinking about making because I don't
think we had the capacity to do it but
having something like that and then
having the person say what's there
stopping point right like marketing
finance these these kind of things and
possibly also having a conference around
that I don't want to get experts on to
deal with that but maybe we get experts
on steel like experts and finance and
how do we get financing and how can we
think outside the boxing game B terms
for financing and how do we do marketing
but they're more meta project meta pain
points meta
things that we all have in common that
we can create solutions floor together
again we need people there to discuss
them in order to actually create them
you really think it's too hot to get
people some amount of people I'm filling
in that spreadsheet I mean yeah we've
done tons of quizzes and tons of things
and they they don't forget like they
don't see it so it's like the language
has to be enough to get them to click on
it to go there or it has to be as simple
as a poll right maybe it is but then I
have to generate maybe it starts with
like well what are your problems like
besides food and clothing you don't even
know your energy your transportation I
don't when when camp can ask when those
were when when you've done those tons of
things what's just like more than a
month ago or so yeah it's more than a
for sure huh but besides yeah like I
mean I mean I put them on on Twitter I
put throwing on my personal Facebook
we've put them out in game B we've put
them out and um like MailChimp quiz it
wasn't mailed cheap ones MailChimp no
something else okay I was like voting
for what the idea Cafe question was
writing that doesn't work instead people
need to be able to have a conversation
to kind of say yes I like that one I
don't like that one it's getting people
to the conversation it's all chicken and
egg problem disappointing three people
you want like thirty people filling that
out not three because what a conference
is a bunch of people yeah and part of it
could be wording and making an easy and
stuff like that but part of it you know
a lot of people are still you know none
of us are really used to solving
problems in this way cuz we're we've
been indoctrinated into this hierarchy
leader led societies ya know it's a bit
of a chicken and egg thing yeah but I do
feel like there's because it's chicken
and egg once you start the egg it grows
into a chicken you got
tons of eggs like it's like it is its
own solution like if we can have one
conference that is repetitive and it's
enjoyable and people know it can be
improved then not only do they hopefully
keep coming back they also bring more
people with them and it does grow and we
have more capacity of people who like oh
I want help with this process if we have
a way to get that information out there
like we need help with this process
because asking for help with the process
doesn't seem to actually help
it's like start the process showcase it
get people on board I don't know I guess
maybe you need to trust combine I mean
how many project Racing's do you have
now three I think
if for each of those project Racing's
you have that project and then all the
participants at least filling in okay
good the participants there were
repetitive but at least there you
already have we have probably six seven
maybe eight different people and then
there are always some two or three more
in the tread they would surely take take
a minute or so to fill out that
spreadsheet and then if you continue
doing that for another month or so then
maybe we might get to 20 and then that
might be already a small egg you know
I'm wondering if we just need to build
participation through the project
raising and other things and then when
we get a little bit bigger than maybe
the conference would yeah might be space
for a conference in project raising that
like the meta like not food because even
though I thought everyone eats that
would be the thing but everyone focus on
people it's maybe not because it's so in
our lives that we can't even see it we
either don't know we have a problem or
we have a problem we have a solution for
it that we are stuck on this solution
maybe trying to have a conference 'king
the game be space if people want to
create a conference for our projects and
maybe that's what I turn the money
because the literally no one has wanted
to join the
Paul so I can turn that into that and
just see what happens you see what if
people are into that into having that be
but that also feels like the food thing
felt very parallel to this so I was like
I can just see if this goes anywhere and
learn something it feels like having
that without you seems weird but since
it's probably gonna be crickets I think
and it's planning the conference right
it's not having the conference and then
whenever the conference is it'll be like
a Saturday morning ends yeah doing it
that way how do you feel about me
changing it to the meta meta project
projects needs to talk about a call
cards for better projects you know I'm
fine with that
fixing the world Friday's was by the way
one of the the key words that really got
me into this a little bit more that
really made me curious because I'm
always thinking in terms of fixing the
world fixing something thank you and
there is a certain amount of like what
I'm learning in life is this thing both
me my just journey and this thing is
happy in its perfect time because fix
the world Fridays or fix our world
Fridays doesn't draw in everyone in fact
it turns off a lot of people but it
turns off the right people and on the
right people who will be brought in and
then it continues on and that NESTA's
what necessarily be the name when you
change and it can reiterate and change
but like there's something when I got
crickets for the food system there was
also this like right we're probably not
supposed to change the food system first
has such a drastic impact in every area
of life than actually having solutions
for and bringing people in might create
a cascade of like we might collapse game
a faster than it needs to be collapsed
whereas in the meta projects growing
them actually kind of is they scaffold
the underneath society that we need in
order to allow for collapse right there
are people tackling the food system
within that space and having I don't
know there was something there that was
like this is
that's right time I just I have to be
patient because I get really frustrated
when it's not going as fast I'm like it
is actually going quite fast it is we're
changing iterations like the things that
happen between Friday and Friday
it's like astronomical it's like okay
even if it's not during this hour
necessarily how do you find it Bentley
speed wise and I'm so self-absorbed with
my own issues that I don't know it's
it's always grindingly slow but that's
just because I've such high expectations
I think this is moving good I mean you
know I've had other like the you know I
think we hit on an idea with the project
raising so I think that's great and then
if we do this kind of meta project
Greece I think that you know if people
like that I think it'd be good and then
yeah I think it would be moving kind of
fast I think it's a good speed I guess
is what I'm saying yeah I you know it
always feels slow so but the fact that
we are getting some progress is great I
mean my other projects I've been working
on since 2011 so you know this is moving
a lot faster than that it's like I guess
I've been working just like you've been
working on from since 2011 I've been
working on mine since 2013-14 and every
time I'm like this is gonna go it's
gonna it doesn't but like it is
happening in its right pace and that's
like my healing journey with my body if
I both got sick very gradually and I'm
getting better very gradually and I feel
like even though everything I do I'm
both terrified it's gonna go viral and
expecting it to go viral I wouldn't be
able to handle if it went viral and this
thing probably will increase
incrementally until there's other people
involved for more of the viral type of
like oh they're the ones who mark it and
get like and that is exactly how it's
supposed to be it's supposed to kind of
be slow Joey and then chicken the eggs
hatched and then it grows up and then it
just explodes and there's no controlling
it then like there is no
the three of us meeting to fix the world
it's you know becomes millions of people
meeting in groups of three in groups of
five and creating their own thing and
using the technology to create their own
projects that have no snowball is very
fast once it starts once we have leaves
genius on this planet and give a certain
amount of collaboration tools it
explodes and there's just like so much
going on you can't know everything
that's going on yeah I don't know I
haven't been paying attention to the
comments money saving I think that's
just gonna distributed problem-solving
groups I think are you muted your neck
sitting here you just said not just that
they should take part in your food
conference on the project raising yes I
don't know master nesto and Esther I
know you I don't want to be on video on
here I think you participated boys
before would you participate in a zoom
conference on video that isn't recorded
I'm just wondering like because ominous
immune extrapolate that to everyone else
doesn't want to be on video but would
like everyone like the millions of
people who don't so those zoom Colts
they are not recorded no I mean it's we
could record them if there's like a few
people in them but once you go into
breakout groups you can't really record
them and we want enough people to go
into breakout groups so that you can
have a comrade small a conversation and
switch people and have you know another
conversation I'm generally for me
personally I'm a fan of recording things
but not necessarily bringing them life
directly like I I sometimes I think it
can be valuable to you know to just look
at something again and give that video
out as a specific reference to people
also I mean I don't mind also having
this one life but
feels a bit weird sometimes yeah and
that's important to honor because if
you're you know I'm being able to say
that there's other people who are even
more that because they're not willing to
be on camera at all and there is a
trade-off for sure doing it and I like
recording if there was I think the idea
with the platform the collaboration
platform if it's facilitating group
video conversations is that you can
record it and it can be made available
but it also doesn't have to be right
that first sown there's millions of them
no one's gonna watch millions of them so
it's it's not one person having millions
of views although maybe it is we'll have
our Joe Rogan's that will be people who
get watched often but mostly it'll be to
look back on right to get to find out
how you've grown or to find out
I don't know AI goes and and figures out
what was decided and takes notes for you
or I don't know I don't know like that's
part of the iteration doing other things
ya know are necessary particularly
better at typing so he's which is also
different people have different ways of
communicating and to find a way to like
bring that together because I don't like
that's harness or I haven't actually had
like I don't think a voice conversation
like what that's not that's the first
point like I need to have a conversation
with someone like I need to either meet
on voice or on video in order to I think
we have actually I think about it but
having um cuz that's how I got saw my
brain works now and I can't really like
even when I type something into game B I
can't stay with the conversation and
keep typing back and forth I'm like I
kinda have to put it and then go then
the next day I can answer a few people's
but and that's not how the internet
works social meeting is very typing but
there's also something lost in that that
everyone needs to do that write that
like on Twitter or everyone yelling back
and forth at each other was it what I
think it would be really good if we can
have both like you know we have our
weekly or bi-weekly meetings and then in
between if there is a better spaced in
Facebook to to communicate
yet about some of those things and then
always maybe in the video meetings we
can one of us maybe can summarize them
or and then talk continue that
conversation because yeah there there
are many people who can express some
things very well on and written and to
bring that in in a better wait and then
how it is right now when you paste in
some selected comments and you also
can't really focus on everything they're
writing and yeah might be helpful and
maybe it may be important it will
definitely increase the scope of people
that reach out to ya know it's
definitely part of the balancing and the
issue is like Facebook isn't great but
it's the best we kind of have because
people are on it I'm on it
you too were on it but there are people
who have emailed me and stuff like I'm
not on Facebook how can I get involved
and like well you can show up but I
don't really know how you get involved
if you're not on Facebook because none
of the other things are a solution from
Facebook like there's discord there's
all these things but they don't have the
people and you have to learn them and
it's like we're kind of on existing
technology on YouTube on Facebook until
we can create our own collaboration
platform then actually is able to do
those things right because that is part
of having a project it's like how do you
get people involved how do you have one
meeting and then also have ideas and do
stuff in between meetings and have new
people come on board and be on board
right of like here is everything that's
happened before without having to sit
through hundreds of hours of videos or
if we if we create our own website
platform that has those videos and a
chat and things integrated do you think
that would actually help or would it
also be something where nobody would
ever show up because nobody knows about
it and all the energy is still in
Facebook yeah I mean that is the life
three of us creating it and then needing
to market anything to fund it is the
chicken and egg problem but if 10,000 of
us got together like if even if a
hundred of us got together because we
have our own projects and we created
something that helps our projects then
it's going to not only help the hundred
projects that we bring to it we're gonna
bring people to it to work on those
hundred projects and it'll work just
with those people is my like you don't
make something in a group that's not big
enough to use it utilize it and fund it
because yeah then you just have the same
problems over and over again but if you
can solve the Mehta problem with it
the Mehta problem solves it for you
because if they're you know what I mean
they're bringing in people to coordinate
on it and like as an individual I want
to work on different projects and have
one dashboard to look at to know my
calendar to know what I'm adding to this
once know what I'm adding to that one
none of the things out there do that
even the project management systems it's
like when you're paying per team but I
I'm not like you know name you know I'm
not on one team I'm gonna be on ten
different projects a tiny event when
whatever it is to create the
collaboration platform means we need to
collaborate to create it which means it
can't be a tiny group of people and it
has to be evolving it has to be
something that we can say what's working
and what's not working and that's where
the scheduling tool it was like the
first idea of the project where it's not
necessarily project management and team
building it's just getting people to a
zoom call right if you have a hundred
people coordinating when they are gonna
meet if you have six people how do you
you know how do you get people to a call
and how do you what is the process of a
conversation that works and then from
there having conversations about what
tools can we add to the next iteration
and the next iteration and constantly
looking to make it better because it's
ours and none of the ones out there that
we don't own together can we do that
with right we can take pieces from this
one and pieces from that one but they
don't integrate properly and so being
able to create something together from
the ground up is the ideas we then own
it and can improve on it and we have
enough people to make it happen but it's
getting those people to make it happen
we're about out of time any closing
comments did we get anywhere close to
answering your questions Jubilee yes and
no I think this is like this felt more
productive than last week just because
we had I feel like we are getting
towards what we're gonna do at this hour
the meta project masterminds a
conference has better projects and
keeping project raising there's
something very powerful there that both
will bring in the people because we're
listening to it's bringing in the people
it's where we are and it's just
enjoyable in every level these have
already been enjoyable for me but like
figuring out how to actually solve
problems I don't regret what or
necessary just called it get rid of
little by little no it was something
else that was the other one I put up on
the screen oh there we go distributive
problem-solving groups like braiding huh
all right well thank you YouTube for
hanging out Thank You Ernesto and till
the capture on whoever else was was here
earlier I think there was three at one
point so thank you and we will see you
next week or tomorrow for project
raising where we are raising Jonas's
project kind act thank you thank you bye
YouTube